Whereas integers are whole numbers, floating
numbers, often referred to as shorts,
are numbers with decimals. In the code example
here, 113-numbers, the multiplier variable on
line 2 is a float data type as it contains
a decimal point. Identifying integers versus
floating decimals is easy, as we all look for
is a decimal point. One facet of any programming
language to know to get accurate calculations is
whether performing arithmetic with an integer and
a float returns a float or an integer. On line
4, I will add a print statement to add these
two variables. I will type print, and then within
parentheses, number_of_tries plus multiplier and
then I will run the code. We get a float. Next,
I will change the operator to multiplication.
We still get a float. The real test is division.
I will change the operator to division and rerun
this code. Even though three divided by 1.5
returns a whole number, 2, it still represents
a float. What we have seen adds to the notion
that Python is a very user-friendly language,
as many older programming languages return
integers when using an integer and a float in
a calculation. When building games in Python
or any other language, when using numbers,
take a moment to determine whether you need
numbers to be integers or floats. For games
with scores, integers are likely. But for games
involving money, you probably need floats.